This video introduces posting groups
which are an important accounting
concept in Business Central. To ensure
efficient and accurate transaction
processes, posting groups link
customers, vendors, and VAT or sales tax
with GL accounts. There are three main
kinds of posting groups. General such as
general business and product posting
groups. Subleddger specific like
customer, vendor, or inventory and VAT
or tax posting groups. Business posting
groups focus on who you do business
with. For example, you can group master
data based on whether it's domestic,
foreign, or whatever fits your
accounting needs. Product posting groups
focus on what you buy or sell. You can
group master data, for example, around
resale, manufacture, or retail. We
combine the who business posting groups
and what product posting groups and
posting setups. For example, when we
sell a retail item to a domestic
customer, the posting setup might point
to the sales revenue and COGS accounts.
Another example is the VAT posting
setup. When we sell an item that uses
the standard VAT rate to a domestic
customer, the sales VAT account is used.
We can assign posting groups to
customers, vendors, and items, or they
can inherit posting groups from
[Music]
templates. Here's an example. We'll open
a sales invoice and choose a
customer. Notice the general and
customer posting groups. These will come
from the customer. The customer posting
group contains a receivable account
where the receivable amount will be
posted in the general
ledger. Now we'll add an item and look
at the general and inventory posting
groups it uses.
Notice that the inventory posting group
contains the inventory account where the
item inventory amount will be
posted. For the general product posting
group, let's look at how it combines
with the customer's general business
posting group. Notice the cogs and sales
accounts. These are where the cogs and
revenue amounts will be posted.
[Music]
Let's preview the posting to see the
ledger entries we'll create. The entry
for the customer is based on the
customer posting group. It contains the
due date, remaining amount and other
relevant information. The entry for the
item is based on the inventory posting
group. It has information like
quantities, sales amounts and so on. The
entry for VAT is based on the VAT
posting setup. For example, it shows the
VAT rate and base amounts. All
subleddger amounts will be reflected in
general ledger
entries. Sales revenue and COGS GL
accounts are taken from the general
posting setup. Sales tax or VATGL
accounts come from the VAT posting
setup. The receivables account comes
from the customer posting group. Now,
let's look at how to post directly to GL
accounts without using subleddgers. We
can choose GL accounts only on lines on
journals and documents. This allows
subleddgers like the customer or
inventory to exist alongside the general
ledger. Posting groups keep subleddgers
in sync with the general ledger. If we
don't use subleddgers and post directly
to a GL account, we can enable direct
posting for the account. For accounts
where direct posting is not enabled, we
can use the where used list to see the
posting groups that use this account.
Thanks again for watching. We've just
seen how posting groups make accounting
less complex when posting transactions
and how we can post exactly what we want
at the general ledger.
[Music]